SHANE LEVITES

Redondo Beach, CA

805-843-1167 | srlevit94@gmail.com https://linkedin.com/in/shanelevites | shanelevites.com

Summary

Software Engineer who identifies and solves problems. Recognized for finding technological solutions to streamline processes and for adapting to evolving compliance standards during ten years in International Education. Can combine past experience with skills acquired from a Certificate in Web Development to help organizations optimize their projects.

Skills

Languages: Git, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), GraphQL

Frameworks: React, Express, CSS Frameworks (Bootstrap, Tailwind) Databases: SQL, MySQL, iQuery, MongoDB and Mongoose, Apollo

Core Concepts: Local and Session Storage, APIs, Object-Oriented Programming Other Skills: Microsoft Office, Google Suite, ChakraUI, Trello, Intermediate Korean

Projects

Back End for E-Commerce (MySQL)

- Repo: https://github.com/srlevit94/E-Commerce-Back-End-Product-DB
- Demo: https://watch.screencastify.com/v/1y0bHlY0XJkTPgFeNXq3
- Uses MySQL to keep a database of Products, the Category they fall into, and associated Tags

Weather App (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs)

- Repo: https://github.com/srlevit94/weather-dashboard-m06
- Deployed App: https://srlevit94.github.io/weather-dashboard-m06/
- Site allows user to enter a city name, then displays that city's weather forecast pulled from the Open Weather API

Team Profile Generator (CLI, JavaScript, CSS)

- Repo: https://github.com/srlevit94/team-profile-generator-m10
- Demo: https://watch.screencastify.com/v/DXMf8fueWbm0qa6CpF6g
- Uses CLI prompts for user to enter data about their team, then generates an HTML page with each member's information within styled cards

Work Experience

University of California, Los Angeles

Pepperdine University

May 2022 - Present

Exchange Visitor (J-1) Counselor, Full-Time

Los Angeles, CA

- Provides J-1 visa-related advising and services for over 3,000 International students and scholars
- Uses Excel, CRMs, and online forms to track exchange visitor data and improve workflows

Feb 2020 - May 2022

International Student Services Specialist / Manager, Full-Time

Malibu, CA

- Used PeopleSoft, Sunapsis, Etrieve, Salesforce, and Google Suite to ensure that ~1000 international students properly obtained and maintained their F-1 visa status
- Served as office manager who also onboarded, trained, and supervised up to 10 student workers
- Creatively implemented procedures and policies to adapt to new regulations and requirements related to COVID-19

English Program in Korea (EPIK)

Aug 2017 - Aug 2019

Middle School English Teacher, Full -Time

Daejeon, South Korea

- Prepared and taught EFL lessons plans for twenty-two sections of Middle School students per week
- Proofread learning and testing materials for language errors and ambiguity

UC Irvine, Division of Continuing Education

June 2015 - Aug 2017

Student Life and Activities Assistant, Full-Time

Irvine, CA

Planned and coordinated programs and events for visiting International Students, helping ensure there was an
activity available nearly every day of the week

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

Awarded Apr 2023

• UCLA Extension Bootcamps

Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages (TESOL) Certificate

Awarded June 2018

• UC Irvine, Division of Continuing Education

B.A. International Studies; B.A Education Science

Awarded June 2015

• University of California, Irvine

UC Education Abroad Program - Seoul, South Korea

Participated Fall 2023

• Yonsei University